<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Submitting data to NMRShiftDB">
	<intro>
		<description>
			This cheat sheet gives you a tutorial on how to submit data to NMRShiftDB. It will guide you through the process of submitting a structure and a spectrum to NMRShiftDB. 
			Note that the order of the steps is partly open to you, also some elements may be omitted either because you get the data from somewhere else or because you do not need them. 
			We will try to make clear where this is the case.
		</description>
	</intro>
	<item title="Step 0: Prerequisites">
		<description>
			You need several Bioclipse plugins to be able to submit data to NMRShiftDB. If you downloaded the Speclipse edition of Bioclipse (branded as Speclipse), you do not need to worry 
			about this. If you have the general Bioclipse edition, you can get the required plugin by installing the Speclipse feature. An update site for that is preconfigured, go to Help -> Search for new Features for installing the Speclipse feature. 
			on http://www.nmrshiftdb.org/ for the final submit. Go to the webpage to register.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Step 1: Creating the structure file">
		<description>
			The first thing you need is a file containing the structure you want to submit. If you do no yet have this from another source, you can use the JChemPaint plugin to draw your structure and save it (we 
			recommand the CML file format). To create a new structure file, use "File"->"New ..."->"Chemistry"->"Molecule" (or use the "Click to perform" below). You can then open the new file by double clicking it and draw the molecule. If you need 
			help on drawing, use the "Help"->"Help Contents"->"JChemPaint". If your spectra include a 1H spectrum, and you want to assign different shifts to protons at the same heavy atom, you need to have explicit protons there. You can make all protons explicit via "JChempaint"->"Edit"->"Hydrogens ..."->"Make all hydrogens explicit" (in your final submission only protons around chiral centers will be visible, though). Once you have finished the structure save it.
		</description>
		<action pluginId="net.bioclipse.nmrshiftdb" class="net.bioclipse.nmrshiftdb.actions.CheatSheetAction" param1="newstruc">
		</action>
	</item>
	<item title="Step 2: Creating the spectrum (or spectra)">
		<description>
			The second thing you need is a file containing the spectrum you want to submit. This can be in JCAMP-DX or CML format. If you do no yet have this from another source, you can use the Spectrum plugin to type your spectrum and save it (we 
			recommand the CML file format). To create a new spectrum file, use "File"->"New ..."->"Spectrum"->"New Spectrum" (or use the "Click to perform" below). After pressing "Finish", you can open the new file by double clicking it and add the desired peaks. 
			If you need help, use "Help"->"Help Contents"->"The Spectrum Plugin". Once you have finished the spectrum save it. If you want several spectra (e. g. different nuclei) for the structure, you need to repeat this step.
		</description>
		<action pluginId="net.bioclipse.nmrshiftdb" class="net.bioclipse.nmrshiftdb.actions.CheatSheetAction" param1="newspec"/>
	</item>
	<item title="Step 3: Creating a literature entry (optional)">
		<description>
			If you do not want to have a literature entry in your submission, you can skip this step. If you want a literature entry, you need to have it in a BibTex file. You can take any BibTex tool you like or
			create one via  "File"->"New ..."->"BibTex"->"New bibtex file". We recommend to use the template. You can then open the new file by double clicking it and copy/paste the template for your literature type and fill it in. Once you have finished save it.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Step 4: Bringing it all together">
		<description>
			You now have got the components you need and just want to combine them. For doing this, create a new "Spectrum and Molecule" file via "File"->"New ..."->"SpecMol"->"New Assigned Spectrum" (or use the "Click to perform" below). You first need to choose a name for your file (it will get the extension cml, so you need to choose a different name in case you already use cml files for 
			structure or spectrum), then to choose the structure to include (normally the one you entered in step1) and finally the spectra (normally the spectra from step 2). Clicking "Finish" will give you a file ending with cml which you can open by double click and which shows you the structure 
			and one of your spectra (you can change between them in the outline view). Almost the only thing left are the assignments.
		</description>
		<action pluginId="net.bioclipse.nmrshiftdb" class="net.bioclipse.nmrshiftdb.actions.CheatSheetAction" param1="newspecmol"/>
	</item>
	<item title="Step 5: Doing the assignment">
		<description>
			You need to assign the peaks in your spectra to atoms in the molecule. If you have a structure and a spectrum open in the "Spectrum and Molecule" view, you need to switch to assignment mode via the button named "Switch assignment mode on/off" in the top toolbar. You can then select a peak in the table 
			and one or more atoms in the structure by clicking on them (for selecting multiple atoms, hold shift). If you have a proton spectrum and you assign a shift to a heavy atom, the shifts will be transferred to all protons at this heavy atom during submit.  If everything is highlighted you want to assign, hit the "Do assignment" button in the top toolbar. Repeat this till everything 
			is assigned. To check, switch the assignment mode off. The assigne peaks are highlighted and if you click on one, the assigned atoms get highlighted. If you have a literature entry, you need to add this to the assigned spectrum resource. Go to the SpecMol menu, choose "Assign Bibtex". The wizard asks you for the filename (this 
			must be the one from step 3), the entry in the file (take the entry from step 3 again) and to which element you want to assign the literature item. Choose spectrum here. Save the assigned spectrum resource.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Step 6: The actual submit">
		<description>
			So, you have got all your data. To submit it, right click on the assigned spectrum file created in Step 4 and choose the "Submit to NMRShiftDB" item. A window pops up which requieres you to fill in certain metadata, if not yet done with the spectrum. After that, you are asked for the NMRShiftDB username and password. If you press "Finish", your data go 
			off to the server. Congratulations and thanks! If you need more detailed info on the actual submit, see the help at "Help"->"Help contents"->"NMRShiftDB plugin"->"About NMRShiftDB plugin"->"Submit to NMRShiftDB".
		</description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>