<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="General Spectrum Cheat Sheet">
	<intro>
		<description>
			This cheat sheet tells you about things you can do with spectra in Bioclipse. 
			Note that each step in this cheat sheet is an independent task, so there is no order and steps do not depend on each other. 
		</description>
	</intro>
	<item title="Step 0: Prerequisites">
		<description>
 			You need the Speclipse feature installed for this (which you have if you read this and installed via the update site).
 		</description>
	</item>
	<item
       href="/net.bioclipse.spectrum/doc/spectrumEditor.html"
       title="Option 1: Analyze spectra">
		<description>
			The spectrum editor shows spectrum files in any of the allowed formats (see help via ? on top of this section for details). By default, spectrum files 
			will open in it. If they do not, right click the file and choose Open with -> Spectrum Editor. The editor gives you an insight 
			into the content of the file. See the help for explanations. If you want to compare several spectra, you can use the 
			Compare Spectra view. Open it with the link below and choose as many peak spectra files as you like in the navigator (hold Ctrl). They 
			will be shown in the same scale (it only makes sense to compare spectra of the same type, e. g. 1H-NMR). Files not 
			containing a peak spectrum will be ignored.
		</description>
		<action pluginId="net.bioclipse.spectrum" class="net.bioclipse.spectrum.action.CheatSheetAction" param1="opencompare"/>
	</item>
	<item
       href="/net.bioclipse.spectrum/doc/spectrumEditor.html"
       title="Option 2: Perform a peak picking">
		<description>
			When a file is open in the spectrum editor, you can perform a peak picking via the "Pick peaks" icon in the toolbar.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item
       href="/net.bioclipse.spectrum/doc/new.html"
       title="Option 3: Creating a new (peak) spectrum">
		<description>
			You can create a new spectrum in Speclipe. In practice, this is restricted to peak spectra since you need to enter 
			the data yourself. See help via ? on top of this section for details.
		</description>
		<action pluginId="net.bioclipse.spectrum" class="net.bioclipse.spectrum.action.CheatSheetAction" param1="newspectrum"/>
	</item>
	<item
       href="/net.bioclipse.spectrum/doc/formats.html"
       title="Option 4: Convert file formats">
		<description>
			If you have a spectrum file open, you can save it in another format using the Save As... option.
		</description>
		<action pluginId="net.bioclipse.spectrum" class="net.bioclipse.spectrum.action.CheatSheetAction" param1="saveas"/>
	</item>
	<item
       href="/net.bioclipse.nmrshiftdb/html/search.html#searchbyspectrum"
       title="Option 5: Find out which structure might be behind an NMR spectrum">
		<description>
			If you have a peak-picked NMR spectrum, you can try to find out what structure was recorded via searching in 
			NMRShiftDB. Right click on your spectrum in the navigator and choose "Spectrum Search in NMRShiftDB...". For 
			details, click ? on top of this section.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item
       href="/net.bioclipse.nmrshiftdb/html/predict.html"
       title="Option 6: Get the NMR spectrum for a structure">
		<description>
			If you want to know what the NMR spectrum of a structure would look like, there are two options: Firstly you can 
			search NMRShiftDB for it. Right-click your structure in the navigator and choose "Download NMR spectra for this molecule...". This 
			will give you a measured, accurate spectrum given it is in NMRShiftDB. If not, you have the second option of predicting the spectrum 
			via "Spectrum Prediction"->"NMR from NMRShiftDB". This will give you a result in any case. In most cases this will closely match the 
			real spectrum, but in rare cases (e. g. exotic elements in your structure) the results can be inaccurate.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item
       href="/net.bioclipse.nmrshiftdb/html/submit"
       title="Option 7: Assign an (NMR-)spectrum and perhapssubmit it to NMRShiftDB">
		<description>
			There is a separate cheat sheet for this. Click the arrow in the top bar of this cheat sheet and choose "NMRShiftDB Submit Cheat Sheet" or 
			read the help available via the ?.
		</description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>
